<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Spicy World</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in</link><description>Welcome to Spicy World by Arpita Ghosh Das. Easy and Simple Recipes make your cooking faster and your food delicious.</description><item><title>Mutton Stew</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/mutton-stew.html</link><description>During summer we generally avoid to eat rich food. But when it comes to mutton, the decision become difficult 😉. For this kind of situation 'mutton stew' is the perfect food for all. The recipe is very simple and have some mild flavours. You will love this when you make it.</description></item><item><title>Pineapple Milkshake</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/pineapple-milkshake.html</link><description>I love the sweetness and juiciness of pineapple in summer. Then why not make a milkshake with this one in a hot afternoon?? Believe me you will love this milkshake more than anything 😊 ... </description></item><item><title>Dum Aloo</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/dum-aloo.html</link><description>We all love to eat 'aloor dom' along with 'luchi' or 'kochuri'. This is our comfort food. It also goes very well with 'pulao' or 'fried rice'. This one is my mom's recipe. She make the tastiest aloor dom ever. Yesterday I tried this recipe and it came out perfectly.Just give it a try.</description></item><item><title>Spicy Macaroni with Mushroom</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/spicy-macaroni-mushroom.html</link><description>Pasta is one of my favourite snack. Last week I had some boiled pasta, cooked sauce and some mushrooms in my fridge. Then I made this dish. I did not follow any particular recipe. But it came out delicious. Make this at your kitchen and surprise your family.</description></item><item><title>Omelet Curry</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/omelet-curry.html</link><description>We all love to eat omelet. My grandma used to make this dish with her love and care. That is why it always turned out so tasty. Today I am sharing this recipe with little changes. Please make this at your home.</description></item><item><title>Mutton Korma</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/mutton-korma.html</link><description>Last weekend I had a party in my house. Among all the foods, the main attraction was Mutton Korma. This dish is very rich itself. Always serve this with light rice item. Just give it a try.</description></item><item><title>Mutton Tarka (Dhaba Style)</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/dhaba-style-mutton-tarka.html</link><description>In India 'dhaba' means roadside food joints. They offer delicious and spicy meals. Among all of their meals, 'tarka-roti' is the famous one. I once ate 'Mutton Tarka' from them and it was super tasty. Last week I try this tarka recipe and reveal that it tastes exactly like 'dhaba tarka'. Just follow the recipe and impress your family.</description></item><item><title>Macher Kalia (Different Style)</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/macher-kalia.html</link><description>We Bengalis are very fond of fish. Our common meal is fish curry and rice. This recipe is one of the fish curry which we make in occasions and gatherings. I already gave you one kaliya recipe and this one is also very tasty. Try this at your home and let me know how it turns out.</description></item><item><title>Macher chop (Fish Croquettes)</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/macher-chop-fish-croquettes.html</link><description>This is one of my favourite snacks in the evening along with tea. You can get this chop from many fast food centers in West Bengal. But today you can make this Bengali style macher chop in your own kitchen. Just follow the recipe and you will get this mouth watering snack very easily.</description></item><item><title>Dry Chili Fish with Mushroom</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/dry-chili-fish-mushroom.html</link><description>This is a very simple and easy recipe. You can serve this as starter or main course. You can also substitute fish with chicken. It tastes delicious. Try this at your home and tell me about your experience.</description></item><item><title>Kheema Biriyani (Minced meat Biriyani)</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/kheema-biriyani-minced-meat-biriyani.html</link><description>In India "biriyani" is a very popular dish. There are plenty of variations in biriyani. The process is a little lenthy but it tastes delicious. Yesterday I took an attempt on making Kheema biriyani, after the entire process I realize it is the easiest one. That is why I am sharing this recipe with you because it is one of the tastiest and easiest biriyani ever. Try this at your home and make yourself special.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Pakora</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/chicken-pakora.html</link><description>How about a crazy snack in a rainy evening ?? Ohh yeaah its Pakora time !! In Kolkata we get this kind of chicken pakora from fast food centers. If you follow this recipe you can get the same flavour from your homemade pakora.</description></item><item><title>Mutton Pulao / Yakhni Pulao</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/mutton-pulao-yakhni-pulao.html</link><description>This recipe is an authentic pulao recipe. In any gathering you can make this dish and it will be blast. This pulao is super tasty and very easy to make. You just have to be perfect about the measurement. Please try this at your home.</description></item><item><title>Stawberry Milkshake</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/stawberry-milkshake.html</link><description>How about a chilled milkshake in a crazy hot afternoon?? Everybody will say "yessss" .. Lets do this with the sweet flavour of strawberry.</description></item><item><title>Dahi Chicken (Ma's recipe)</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/dahi-chicken.html</link><description>"Lajawab" is the only compliment about mom's recipe. My mom make this dish in a very easy and simple way. But it tastes delicious. You will need very few ingredients for this dish. This the best recipe for teenagers because its very easy to make.</description></item><item><title>Lassi (Yogurt smoothie)</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/lassi.html</link><description>Lassi is the most popular drink of Punjab, India. Nowadays we can get lassi almost everywhere. Its a very refreshing drink during summer. Flavoured lassi are also easily available in the market. But I personally prefer plain lassi. Just follow this recipe and you will get the best lassi from your kitchen.</description></item><item><title>Singara (samosa)</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/singara-samosa.html</link><description>In India samosa is a very popular appetizer. We call it "singara" in West Bengal. Almost every evening my grandpa brought samosas from roadside shop and they were delicious. Last week I made samosas at home (inspired by my mother and husband) and they came out really tasty. So, please try this recipe at your home and impress your family.</description></item><item><title>Hara Bhara Kabab (Green Vegetable Kabab)</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/hara-bhara-kabab.html</link><description>Yesterday my husband was craving for some snacks in afternoon. I had some boiled potatoes in my fridge. Then I thought about this recipe. You can say its fried kabab. After eating this he said you should upload the recipe ☺️. So, its very easy to make. Just give it a try.</description></item><item><title>Dhaba style egg curry</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/dhaba-style-egg-curry.html</link><description>In India we all love "dhaba" foods and also we love eggs. Mostly their dishes are spicy. So, today I am sharing this spicy dish with you. Please try this at your home.</description></item><item><title>Bhapa Doi (Baked Yogurt) - Mango flavour</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/bhapa-doi.html</link><description>"Doi" is a very popular dessert among Bengalis. But "bhapa doi" is a very traditional Bengali dessert. My grandma used to make this in pressure cooker and it tastes super delicious. Today I am sharing both pressure cooker method and oven method with a little twist of mango flavour. My 1st compliment on this dish was "Bengali Cheesecake" from my man :) .... So, please try this and impress your family members.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Tandoori</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/chicken-tandoori.html</link><description>This dish dont need any explanation. Its very popular in India and nowadays all over the world. There was a rumor that without "tandoor/oven" you cannot make tandoori. But believe me today I am sharing "oven method and gas method" of making tandoori.  Please give it a try at your home and prove the rumor wrong.</description></item><item><title>Kasuri Methi Murg Masala</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/kasuri-methi-murg-masala.html</link><description>I made this dish yesterday and it was a blast. So, I am sharing this recipe with you. Please give it a try and let me know about your experience.</description></item><item><title>Vegetable Biriyani</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/vegetable-biriyani.html</link><description>This dish dont need any explanation. Because its 'Biriyani'. Just give it a try and impress your family.</description></item><item><title>Baked Chicken Legs</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/baked-chicken-legs.html</link><description>This is a mouth watering snack recipe. Please try this at your home and surprise your family and guest.</description></item><item><title>Matar Paneer Pulaao</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/matar-paneer-pulaao.html</link><description>This is a variation in rice main course item. In many gatherings you can make this and impress your guest.</description></item><item><title>Palak Kichdi</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/palak-kichdi.html</link><description>When you are in a mood of healthy eating, just give it a try ... This is a very tasty meal.</description></item><item><title>Ghugni or Yellow peas curry</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/ghugni.html</link><description>Its a delicious vegetarian curry. It is also called yellow peas curry. You can also eat this as snack.</description></item><item><title>Kadai Paneer</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/kadai-paneer.html</link><description>This is a very delicious dish. The main attraction here is Kadai masala. It gives such a nice flavour in this dish. Please try this at your home.</description></item><item><title>Paneer (Indian Cottage Cheese)</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/paneer.html</link><description>In vegetarian world paneer plays a very important role. But in nonvegrtarian world it also offers some special dishes. Homemade paneer has its own frshness and taste. So, lets see the recipe.</description></item><item><title>Beguni (Crispy Eggplant Fritters)</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/beguni.html</link><description>This is a famous snack item in Bengal. You need very few ingredients. Make this at your home and enjoy the crunch.</description></item><item><title>Musur daaler Bora (Red lentil fritters)</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/musur-daaler-bora.html</link><description>We can call this comfort food. Because you can make this with very simple ingredients and it tastes yummy.</description></item><item><title>Watermelon Smoothie</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/watermelon-smoothie.html</link><description>During summer it is a very healthy drink. This needs very few ingredients. Hope you will like it.</description></item><item><title>Chicken dak bunglow</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/chicken-dak-bunglow.html</link><description>The name of this recipe is very funny. But it tastes delicious when you make this with your love and care. Lets give it a try.</description></item><item><title>Mutton er laal jhol (Mutton Curry)</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/mutton-curry.html</link><description>This one is a Bengali mutton recipe. Almost every Sunday they make this curry as lunch or dinner. Its my pleasure to share this recipe with you. Please try this once.</description></item><item><title>Banana Smoothie</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/banana-smoothie.html</link><description>During summer it is a very healthy drink. This needs very few ingredients. Hope you will like it.</description></item><item><title>Fish Kaliaa</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/fish-kaliaa.html</link><description>Its a delicious non vegetarian main course dish. This is a Bengali recipe. Hope you will like it.</description></item><item><title>Simple Murgir Jhol (Chicken curry)</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/chicken-curry.html</link><description>Its a delicious main course item. You can make this at your home with very simple ingredients. Everybody will love this recipe.</description></item><item><title>Aloo Posto (Potato with Poppy seed gravy)</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/aloo-posto.html</link><description>Its a simple veg main course dish. This is a very popular bengali recipe. You will like it.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Salad Sandwich</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/chicken-salad-sandwich.html</link><description>Its a very healthy dish. You can make this any time at your home.</description></item><item><title>Basonti Pulaao</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/basonti-pulaao.html</link><description>Its a traditional bengali dish. "Basanti" means yellow colour. They make this in many gatherings. You can also call this as sweet pulao.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Lollipop</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/chicken-lollipop.html</link><description>Its a spicy and delicious nonvegetarian starter item. This one is a Chinese style recipe. You will like it.</description></item><item><title>Mutton Kosha (bengali style)</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/mutton-kosha.html</link><description>Its a delicious nonveg main course dish. This is a Bengali style recipe. In many gatherings they make this dish. Its a very popular item. You should try this.</description></item><item><title>Hot and Sour Soup (Chicken and Egg)</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/hot-sour-soup.html</link><description>Its a chinese non vegetarian starter item. This is a very tasty dish. If you like spicy you have to try this one.</description></item><item><title>Mango Smoothie</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/mango-smoothie.html</link><description>Its a very refreshing drink in summer. In India we call this Mango Lassi. It needs very simple ingredients. You can make this any time at your home.</description></item><item><title>Fried Rice</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/fried-rice.html</link><description>Its an delicious vegetarian main course dish. Its a complete meal with vegetables. Everybody loves to eat fried rice.</description></item><item><title>Mutton Biriyani</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/mutton-biriyani.html</link><description>Its a famous non vegetarian main course dish. In India biriyani is a very popular item. Hope you like it.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Korma</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/chicken-korma.html</link><description>Its an awesome non vegetarian main course dish. In India its a very popular dish. We make this in many occasions. Hope you will like it.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Biriyani</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/chicken-biriyani.html</link><description>Its a famous non vegetarian main course dish. In India biriyani is a very popular item. Hope you like it.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Roll</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/chicken-roll.html</link><description>Its an awesome non vegetarian snack item. You can also say its a complete snack because it has chicken and paratha. Hope you will like it.</description></item><item><title>Egg Chicken Chowmein</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/egg-chicken-chowmein.html</link><description>Its a delicious non vegetarian dish. You can serve it as snack or main course item.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Malai kebab</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/chicken-malai-kebab.html</link><description>Its a mouth watering non vegetarian snack item. You will love it.</description></item><item><title>Egg Curry</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/egg-curry.html</link><description>Its a yummy non vegetarian main course dish. Everybody loves egg. So lets try this curry ...</description></item><item><title>Chicken kali mirch</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/chicken-kali-mirch.html</link><description>Its a delicious non vegetarian main course dish.</description></item><item><title>Palak Paneer</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/palak-paneer.html</link><description>Its a yummy main course vegetarian dish.</description></item><item><title>Kadai Chicken</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/kadai-chicken.html</link><description>Its a main course dish.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Tikka Kebab</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/chicken-tikka-kebab.html</link><description>Its an awesome starter dish.</description></item><item><title>Fish Mustard Curry</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/fish-mustard-curry.html</link><description>Its a main course dish.</description></item><item><title>Chana masala</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/chana-masala.html</link><description>Its a main course dish. Also called Curry of Garbanzo Beans</description></item><item><title>Paneer Makhani</title><link>http://www.spicyworld.in/paneer-makhani.html</link><description>Its a main course dish. Paneer is also called Indian cottage cheese.</description></item></channel></rss>